那就是我，在25岁生日 从西弗州的维灵架道奇车
So there I am, on my 25th birthday, driving from wheeling,
到本斯河，没有收音机 只有个叫“桶盖”的走私枪械的家伙
west virginia to bensonhurst in a dodge dart with no radio and a gun runner named barrelhead
坚持要唱所有他能想起来的 布吉米的歌
who insisted we sing every jimmy buffet song he could recall
我能说什么？那家伙火力装备猛烈
What can I say? The man was heavily armed
500首旧歌过后 我的首张封面
So 500 renditions of margaritaville later, my first cover
就用了8000字描述桶盖和 他的朋友们运送手枪卖到纽约的事
8,000 words on how barrelhead and his friends were transporting handguns for sale to new york city
那天杂志在售卖点爆棚 检察官跟我较上了劲
The day the magazine hit the stands, the D.A. Hit me with a subpoena
他要知道桶盖具体的名字
He wanted to know barrelhead's real name
格塔跟编辑蘑菇了三天
Greta had been managing editor for three whole days
她邀请我去对街的诡异酒吧 他们有真的玻璃杯
So she invited me across the street to the fancy bar, where they use real glasses
喝过6杯伏特加和汤尼水
And after about the sixth vodka and tonic
她说“福莱，我想让你知道 杂志支持你”
she said, "fletch,I want you to know the magazine is behind you."
我很感动
Well,I was impressed
我说“你觉得你能帮我 摆脱检察官么？”
I said,"do u think you can get the da off my back?"
她说“不能，但是当你出狱后 你依然有工作”
And she said,"no. But when you get out of jail, you'll still have a job."
我45岁了，放弃了很多
I'm 45. I've given up a lot
放弃了道路，那样的人生 谢谢，贝兹，不遗憾
I've given up the road, that life. Thanks,elizabeth.No regrets
我可爱的妻子，我放弃了酗酒 放弃了毒品
My lovely wife.I've given up drinking. I've given up drugs
格塔教我两件事不能戒除
Greta taught me there's two things you never give up
一个是摇滚，一个是消息来源 斯格塔
One's rock and roll. The other's a source.Greta sims
-美好会议，格塔 -我们会想念你的格塔
-Great memories,greta -We'll miss you,greta. We'll miss you
我希望没了压力，你能--
I only hope you can adjust to the lack of stress in your--
福莱！
fletch!
福莱，福莱……
Fletch! Fletcher.Fletch. Fletcher. Fletcher!
甜心，你没事吧?
Honey,sweetie. Are you okay?
-哦，你没事吧?
-@#￥&^×@ -Oh! Are you okay? -I flung the investment
你说什么?
What did you say?
@#￥％^&
I flung the investment
-！@#￥％％^^？ -我要打911了
-Why consign? Why consign? -I'll call 911
～！@#
It's proficient
！@#￥％％?
Why disqualify the rush? I'm tabled
&^％￥#@！～
I'm tabled
我需要你的建议
I need your advice
-60英里之内最好的诊断中心是哪? -我们
-What's the best diagnostics department within 60 miles of here? -We are
“我们”不在这 豪斯在巴尔的摩弄他的医疗补助账单
"We" aren't here.House is in baltimore lying to medicaid about his billings
-那又怎样？我也合格啊 -你不是豪斯
-So? I'm board certified -You are not house
如果你觉得我不合格 干嘛让我当负责人?
Why'd you put me in charge of the department if you think I can't handle it?
因为是暂时的，因为有人命令我
Because it's temporary, and because I was ordered to
-什么症状? -哦，算了吧
-What are the symptoms? -Oh,come on
不见人你就想给诊断 证明你跟豪斯一样棒？
You're gonna diagnose him without meeting him? Prove that you're as brilliant as house?
我得知道症状才能推荐医院
I need to know the symptoms to know which hospital to recommend
急救报告：病人撞了头后患了失语症
Emt's report-- patient struck his head and is suffering from aphasia
恩，神经学问题
Hmm,neurological problem
那个领域我知道不少好人会认同 我碰巧就是个专家
I know a lot of good people in that field seeing as I happen to be a neurologist
－你生气了 －我没有
-You're pouting -Not at all
泰勒不错，豪斯在得到我的简历前 本来是要雇佣他的
Taylor's pretty good.House was ready to hire him till he got my resume
是石福莱，写了12本书 曝光了三个政府部门
It's fletcher stone.Wrote 12 books? Exposed three administrations.
－在他曝光我们之前…… －明白了，著名的病人配著名医生
-Before he exposes us-- I get it.Famous patient needs famous doctor
-我打给泰勒 -谢谢
-I'll call taylor -Thank you
要不还是你打给他吧
Or maybe you should call him
万一我说了蠢话怎么办?
What if I say something stupid?
哦，天啊，还是豪斯比较好相处
Oh,god.House is easier
-用过药品么? -我功能移位了
-Have you been taking any drugs? -I displaced my function. Accolade
他过去有规律地饮酒 但戒除已近一年
He used to drink regularly, but he's been clean and sober for nearly a year
石先生，你以为自己说话正常 但其实是讲话能力减弱了
Mr. Stone,you think you're speaking normally,but your speech is impaired
他知道自己要说的话 但选择词汇时发生错误
He knows what he wants to say,but when he reaches for a word, he finds something else
#￥￥％^&％^％
I grapple average
-％￥#@&× -他不知道自己说错了么?
-Tanzer glisten -He doesn't know that he's saying it wrong?
对他来说没什么问题
It all sounds right to him
我需要你写下自己的名字 然后画一张脸
I want you to write your name and draw a face
这叫失写症，失去写的能力 多数是暂时性的
It's called agraphia. oss of ability to write. Most often it's temporary
-他撞的到底有多狠? -撞的挺狠，声音怪吓人的
-How hard did he hit his head? -It was a pretty good crack.It made a really ugly sound
-你明白我说的意思么? -@#￥％
-do you understand what I'm saying? -Of golf
别跟我说句子，回答是、不就行了 懂我意思吗？
Don't give me a sentence.Just say yes or a no.You understand me?
是
Yes
-贝兹，福莱，他没事么？ -还不知道，这是福莱的编辑
-Elizabeth. Fletch. Is he okay? -We don't know.This is fletch's editor
斯格塔，我要保证急救报告陈述正确
Greta sims.I wanted to make sure that the emts told you the right story
-有多少陈述啊? -他不是绊倒的，是倒下去了 失去知觉了
-How many stories are there? -He didn't trip.He just fell.Out of the blue
他的脚先拐了一下，看上去象是绊的
His foot jerked a little bit first.That's what made it look like a trip
别说，别谈你账单的事 因为没有辩护余地
don't say anything.Don't attempt to defend your billing practices.Your billing practices are indefensible
-我们都了断这个了 -如果我真认为你能听进去人话 我就住嘴了
-We've been over this -If I thought you were capable of listening,I'd shut up
那完全没有道理
That makes no sense at all
-下午好 -下午好
-Good afternoon -Good afternoon
难易表上有达到五级的情况吗？
Every case you have rates a five on the complexity scale?
豪斯医生有特殊需要
Dr. House has a rather specialized practice
好，那我们来完成这个吧
Okay. Then let's go through these
-所有吗? -如果你有午餐聚会，取消吧
-All of these? -If you have lunch reservations, cancel them
好，病人...
All right. Patient...
如果不是绊倒的，怎么摔的？ 中风？抽搐？
if he didn't trip, something made him fall. Stoke? Seizure?
30个人看见他绊倒了 一个人说不是，你信谁？
30 people saw him trip.One person says he didn't. Who you gonna believe?
他所有的症状用头外伤都可以解释
His symptoms can all be explained by the head trauma
导致外伤和抽搐，那又导致失语症 该做个脑电图
Causes a contusion or a seizure.That causes the aphasia. We should get an eeg
-如果是中风，就有凝块问题 -就算是跌倒，药品问题也比较象
-If it was a stroke, it could be a clotting issue -Even if he fell, drug use is far more likely
-我定一个氧化监视检查 -小蔡，我们还没完成细分呢
-I'm ordering a tox screen -Chase,we're not done with the differential
-你不是我的老板 -我是豪斯的老板，豪斯是你的老板
-You're not my boss -I'm house's boss.House is your boss
-简单算数 -是你发我工钱吗?
-The math is pretty simple -Are you signing my paychecks?
-雇人炒人归你管么? -这不是那回事儿……
-Are you hiring or firing? -This is not about that--
唯一需要你督导的是防止豪斯做疯事
the only thing you've been asked to do is supervise house in case he does something insane
没准能救人一命
Which might,you know, save a life
-得有人负责啊 -为什么?
-Somebody's gotta be in charge -Why?
你觉得我们可以任意作为吗? 来个诊断比赛
You think we should all just do whatever we wanna do? Maybe have a race to the diagnosis
我觉得同仁中也该有个商量
I think it should be a discussion among peers
我觉得我们够岁数达成共识了
I think we're grown up enough to reach a consensus
病人，62岁，你开了vi的处方
Patient,62 years old.You prescribed viagra
我在史多丽的病例里居然发现了 勃起障碍的处方
I look in vain for the words erectile dysfunction in the notes for delores smith
她心脏有问题
She had a heart condition
-你没有硝酸甘油了吗 -她还血压低
-And you ran out of nitroglycerin? -She also had low blood pressure
所以硝酸甘油会有危险 而小蓝药片就可以兼顾了
So nitro would be dangerous.Little blue pills improve blood flow
是舒张血管的，所以有时你会头疼
They're vasodilators.It's why you sometimes get the headaches.
-我想豪斯医生明白了 -当然
-I think dr. House understands -of course I do
-那女人心脏有问题，她得照顾自己 －一个男人无法抓紧他的助手 这是民族的危急时刻
-The woman has a heart condition she's on her own -A man can't nail his office assistant,it's national crisis time
你真的认为我们会为 用途外的药品用途付钱么？
Are you seriously expecting us to foot the bill for off-label use of medication?
行，我来付，多少钱?
Fine. I'll pay for it.How much are the pills?
-她吃了多少? -把钱拿开
-She took how many? -Put the money away.
-你想贿赂我吗? -不
-Are you trying to bribe me? -No
-我可以的，大厅里有提款机 -我的客户是个白痴
-I could.Thers an atm in the lobby -My client's an idiot
但他是否错开了药呢?
But is he wrong about the pills?
-我们不认同用途外的处方 -你再有3周就退休了
-Off-label use is not sanctioned -You're retiring in three weeks
你干这行都快20年了，难道你对自己 都不认可的管理条例不厌烦吗？
You've been doing this job nearly 20 years.Aren't you tired of administering policy you disagree with?
-我没说不同意 -他们能把你怎么样?
-I never said I disagree -What can they do to you?
而且豪斯医生对于早先的发作很抱歉
And dr. House is sorry about his earlier outburst
没错
Absolutely
你亲自对医疗补助制度作背景调查了?
You do background checks on medicaid personnel?
我会为我的客户做任何需要做的 哇，新记录耶
I do what's necessary for my client. Wow,new personal reco.
对，时间对我也挺合适 我在港口的食堂有个小预订
Yeah,timing's good for me too.I got a reservation at a little place in the inner harbor
-你给我们顶了午餐? -马丽岛最好的螃蟹在……马丽岛
-You booked us dinner reservations? -Best maryland crab in...maryland
-你没计划着自己抓吗? -几个小时没想了
-Don't you have a plane to catch? -Not for hours
你的班级7点起飞
Your flight leaves at 7:00.
你查我背景了吗?
You did a background check on me?
我的9点才走，看来你要自己吃饭了
-And mine doesn't leave till 9:00pm.It looks like you'll be dining alone
你查了我的班机好确保你自己走
You checked on my flight so you could be sure to be on a different one
-我以为我们已经过了回避阶段 -我不觉得会这么快
-I thought we were past the avoidance stage -I didn't think we'd be finished this soon
-你的十字架呢? -放首饰店清洗
-Where's your crucifix? -I left it at the jewelers to be cleaned
对
Right
这会显示你的颈动脉是否有凝块
This will show us if there's a problem with your carotid artery that might cause a blood clot
如果大脑有，就可以解释失语和跌倒
If it went to his brain, that could explain the aphasia and the falling down
-你还要做脑电，是同样的用途吗？ -哦，是预防
-And you're giving him an eeg?Is that for the same thing? -Uh,it's just a precaution
我想外伤导致了问题 得等他稳定会慢慢复原
I think the trauma caused some swelling, and we need to keep him stable until the body can repair the damage
-而你觉得他俩都错了? -我们涉及全面预防，小心为妙吧
-And you think they're both wrong? -we're just covering all the bases.Being safe
他的02sats降低了
His o2 sats are going down.
-肺部积液 -推40单位的lasix.
-Fluid in his lungs -Push 40 iv lasix.
我们要插管，他失去呼吸功能了
We need to intubate.He's losing his respiratory drive
现在有两个症状了，失语和肺部积液 抽搐无法满足两个症状
and then there were two.Aphasia and fluid in the lungs.Seizure can't cause both
-中风也不行 -除非他有反常心率
-Neither can a stroke -Unless he had an abnormal heart rhythm
还有，尿检显示安非他明阳性
and then there was one.Urine test is positive for amphetamines
-安非他明不导致肺水肿 -如果抽就会
-Amphetamines don't cause pulmonary edema -They do if you smoke 'em.
他的一本书里提到戒酒戒毒 改变人生
In one of his books he talked about giving up drugs and alcohol, how it changed his life.
所有人都撒谎
Everybody lies
当他准备倾听的时候 该能看出来他是个嫉妒的类型
When he started wanting to hear every minute of my day, it should have been a clue he was the jealous type
但在两人关系中的那个阶段
But you know,in that first stage of a relationship
你身体里充满化学物质 觉得一切都是可爱的
where it's like your body's full of these chemicals that make you think everything they do is charming--
啊，对不起
Ah.Excuse me
-喂? -嘿，甜心，孩子们怎样？想我了吗？
-Hello? -Hey,honey,how are the kids?They miss me?
这得打一会儿呢
This may take a minute
-失语症先生有什么新进展? -卡迪打电话给你了?
-so what's new with mr. Aphasia? -Cuddy called you?
有人掩护他们的屁股
Everybody covers their ass
肺水肿，小蔡作了氧化监视 安非他明呈阳性
Pulmonary edema.Chase did a tox screen.It came back positive for amphetamines
-他跳起胜利之舞 -我打赌也有毛病
-He did the dance of victory -I'm betting there's another shoe
我以为孩子们不打给你呢
I thought the kids didn't call you
我了解你讲故事的路子
I know the way you tell stories.
福满找石福莱谈毒品的问题 发现他发烧了
Foreman went to talk to stone about his drug test,found him running a temperature
所以不是药的事，节律都错了
So it's not the drugs.They've just got such a bad rep.
甜心，你不该那样做
Honey,you shouldn't do that
－好，我挂了，他们该找我了 -你没有电话等?
Okay,I gotta hang up.They're probably trying to reach me -You don't have call waiting?
-我挂你的电话 -每月五块
-I'm hanging up on you now -It's $5.00 a month
药物不导致高烧
Drugs don't cause fever.
脑炎或脑膜炎最可疑 给抗生素吧
Encephalitis or meningitis are the obvious suspects.Start him on antibiotics
可能是自体免疫问题 狼疮什么的，我们该给他上类固醇
It could be an autoimmune disease.Lupus,behcet's. We could start him on a high dose of steroids.
如果他确实有脑炎 类固醇会削弱他的免疫系统
Except if he does have encephalitis, Steroids could weaken his immune system
-福满 -烧有多高?
-Foreman -How high a fever?
把扬声器打开 你干嘛不给我电话呢？
Put me on speaker phone.And why haven't you called me?
101.你怎么知道?
101.How'd you know?
怎么？你以为你们这帮孩子父母一走 就开派对，而我不会听说？
What?You think you guys can have a party as soon as the parents are gone,and I won't hear about it?
给上广谱抗生素防止脑膜炎病菌和 滤过性病毒
Start with broad spectrum antibiotics for possible bacterial meningitis
他得的是疱疹脑炎
and an antiviral in case we luck out, and it's herpes encephalitis
-如果是自体免疫怎么办? －那我们就玩完了
-What if it's autoimmune? -Well,then we're screwed
所以我们才需要更多资料 有家族遗传么？
Which is why we need more information.Any genetic issue with the family?
－他无法谈话，病例很粗略 -他妻子只认识他没几年
the man can't talk.His medical records are sketchy. -And the wife's only known him a couple of years
-核磁共振怎样? -Ct 扫描隐形
-mri show anything? -Ct scan was negative.
Ct?是短核磁么？
Ct? That's,like, short for mri,right?
太好了，能省不少时间
Excellent.That'll save us a lot of time.
我们约了20分钟后的核磁，福满只能约 到这了
We've got an mri scheduled in 20 minutes.Earliest foreman could get the machine
我教了你们骗、撒谎、偷 可我一转脸你们就排起队来了
I teach you to lie,cheat,and steal, and as soon as my back is turned you wait in line?
-做核磁，找病例 -他不能说话
-Get an mri,and get a better medical history -The man can't talk
谁管？他总归是要说谎的 我的航班晚了一会儿，几小时后到
Who cares?He's probably gonna lie anyway. My flight's a little late.I'll be back in a few hours.
你管我们因为你管他？
So you're in charge of us because you're in charge of him?
-家族病史有神经系统问题吗? -没有
-Any family history of neurological problems? -No
-这五年内没出国？ -对
-You've been out of the country in the last five years -Yes
-三年? -对
-Three years? -Yes
两年
Two years
两年前当我们关系确定后他就不出差了
He stopped traveling for work two years ago after we got serious
-假期? －六个月前最后一次
-Any vacations? -His last one was six months ago
-比湾的高尔夫球会 -不会是高尔夫球会
-It was a golf resort at key biscayne -No way it was a golf resort
对他的了解，我看是他很快喝遍了 能找到的酒吧
Knowing fletch,I assume he was working his way through every bar in the keys
没坐下就喝多了
Last hurrah befo settling down
-酒精? -没
-Alcohol? -No
-安非他明 -没
-Amphetamines -No
你的检查是阳性
You tested positive
他不用药品
he doesn't use drugs.I told you
我们订婚时说了，要过不同的日子
When we got engaged, we decided we wanted a different kind of life
他放弃了男性杂志，没了疯狂的机会
And he dropped the macho journalism.No more taking crazy chances
包括他的身体
That includes his health
他不让我告诉贝兹
he asked me not to tell elizabeth
他对她隐瞒了药品习惯?
He's been lying to her about his drug habit?
是也不是，在婚前，他老用药
Well,yes and no.Be--before elizabeth-- he used drugs recreationally
我不喜欢，但就是那哆哆嗦嗦的行为 才使他有今天的声望
I wasn't crazy about it, but that thrill-seeking behavior is what made him the kind of journalist that he was
-现在呢? -他为她痴迷
-And now,ae? -The man's twisted himself into knots for her
改过自新
Completely cleaned up his act
-可药品? -是有益的
-But the drugs? -They're medicinal
有点，他有睡眠问题
Sort of.He was having trouble sleeping.
他的新式乡村生活没有刺激 使他难受
His new suburban lifestyle.Lack of excitement was throwing him off
所以就吃安眠药
So he started with sleeping pills
被它们击倒后他需要在白天时提神
When they knocked him out, he needed something to perk him back up during the day
每天？下滑的太快了
Every day?No slippery slope there
！@##￥￥％
Keep the stain.Knife can't force
我们不会告诉你妻子，我们不是警察
We'rnot gonna tell your wife.We're not cops
有点水肿，脑积液 区域内有疤痕
There's a little edema.Brain swelling.And an area of scarring
-是失语的成因吗? -其实，那很奇怪
-Is that what's causing the aphasia? -Actually,that's what's odd
疤痕并不在导致失语的区域之内
The scarring's not in the area of the brain normally associated with conduction aphasia.
而且是旧伤，撞头之前就有
And it's old.Happened before he hit his head
也许是一次小的中风或其他情况 也许根本无关
Maybe a small stroke or some other underlying condition that cou be causing this, or it might have nothing to do with it at all
以前有过头外伤吗？事故？
Have you ever had head trauma before?An accident?
过去有过一侧麻痹吗?
You ever had any numbness on one side before?
-头晕? -！@#￥％?
-Dizziness? -What is the durable?
没有
no
870航班乘客飞机延误一个半小时
passengers for flight number 870.The plane will be delayed by one half-hour... thanks
给你弄了咖啡
Got you some coffee
你想谈什么?
So what do you wanna talk about?
核磁上的疤痕可能是任何东西 上百种病毒
The scarring on the mri could be anything. Ms,toxins, any one of a hundred demyelinating diseases
如果是脑炎，我们得赶快确定细菌
If it's meningitis, we have to id the bug fast
-我们需要腰椎穿刺 -我不会给水肿作LP的
-We need to do a lumbar puncture -I'm not doin lp with this edema
-可能会导致瘫痪 -豪斯怎么说?
-We could paralyze him -What does house say?
"你所拨打的用户已关机或超过服务区"
"The person you're trying to reach is out of the area or has turned off their phone."
那你的意思呢?
So what are your orders?
-需要更多资料 -没资料了
-We need more information -There is no more information
我们闯他家
We'll break into his place
好好玩
Have fun
-病人怎样? -不错
-How's the patient? -Fine
-你去哪? -午饭
-Where you going? -dinner
-哦，我可以参加，那样快点 -抱歉，只定了两个位
-Oh,well I'll join you.You can bring me up to speed -Sorry.Reservation for two
当人们展示自己时是通过小事情看的
when people give themselves away, it's by little things
那边的那个女人，她不是看不起咖啡 她正从面瘫康复中
That woman over there, she's not sneering at her coffee.She's recovering from bell's palsy
咖啡馆收费的女人不想让人知道 可她就快因als死去了
The cashier at the coffee place, she doesn't want anyone to know, but she's dying of als
她的手臂那种特定的僵硬方式是证明
There's a particular sort of twitchy stiff arm that's characteristic
然后是你
And then there's you
干嘛带十字架?
Why aren't you wearing your cross?
-我告诉你…… -你把首饰清洗剂放在水槽边 就是为了能整天带着它
-I told you,I left it at-- -you keep jewelry cleaner under the sink so you won't have to go a day without it
对，可你忘了早晨水管爆了
True,you forgot it that morning the pipes burst
可你又涉水回去找到了
But then you went back and waded through the flood to retrieve it
那干嘛今天不带?
So why no wading today?
你就不带本书看什么的么？
Didn't you bring a book to read or something?
没
Nothing
咖啡因、安非他明 他跟我们说用的一样
Caffeine pills and amphetamines.Same stuff he told us he was taking
和联苯酚
And topamax
抗惊厥药？他说没有抽搐病史？
An anti-convulsant?He said there was no history of prior seizure
甚至不是开给他的
It's not even prescribed to him
-还是无法解释高烧，也许是减肥的吧 -再给我们个谎言吧
-Still doesn't explain his fever.Probably just using it for weight loss -Just gives us another lie
他真有献身精神 是不是该查他家啊?
He must really be devote. should we check the home?
如果他要瞒着他的妻子 干嘛不把东西藏办公室啊?
If he wanted to hide something from his wife, why wouldn't he hide it in the office?
也许她要隐瞒什么
Maybe she's hiding something
浴室只有阿斯匹林和感冒药
Nothing but aspirin and flu meds in the bathroom
这东西好像搁这好几个星期了
Looks like this stuff's been sitting here for weeks
嗯，家庭改进，他大概以为可以继续
hmm,home improvement.He probably thought he could take the project on
后来意识到超过他的能力
then realized it was a little more than he could handle
你要说重点，还是想 给个非医学的、冗长的无聊演讲？
You got a point to make, or did you just feel like giving a long, unnecessary explanation for something medically irrelevant?
永远有答案的福满怎么了?
What happened to the foreman who always has an answer?
那个老挂着牌子“我跟豪斯一样棒， 可比他友善”的家伙
The guy who practically wears a sign saying,"I'm as good as house, but I'm nicer."
-我没那么说 －我猜有他在那反驳你 会更安全和自信吧
-I never said that -I guess it's safe to be confident when house is there to overrule you
-现在全靠你了? -是不一样了，是的
-Now that it's all on you? -It's different. Yeah.
106航班去那维延误...
Flight 106 to Nashville has been delayed...
你是故意不带的
either you left it behind on purpose or by mistake.
而你故意不带的意思是 它对你已经没有意义了
The only reason you'd leave it behind intentionally is if it no longer meant anything to you
而那是你妈妈的礼物 意思是你跟她吵架了
But since it was a gift from your mom, that would mean you had a fight with her
而你又不能跟鬼说话，所以也不是
And since you don't talk to ghosts,that's unlikely
-算了，格里 -对，那我很在行
-Leave it alone,greg -Yeah,m good at that
那么忘记就不是故意的
So that leaves forgetting it unintentionally
那我们又要解释为什么你没回去取
But then we have to explain why you didn't go back for it when you realized
-我到了机场才发现 -不对，你到机场时化装了
-I didn't realize until I got to the airport -Nope,you were wearing makeup when you got to the airport
你无法不看自己就化装
You can't put on makeup without looking at yourself
你看自己而没摸那个东西也不可能
You can't look at yourself without touching that thing
-为什么这干你的事? -这不寻常，不寻常的事打扰到我
-Why does this matter to you? -It's an anomaly.Anomalies bug me
那你就难受着吧
Then you're gonna suffer
-我看是他的胃 -！@#￥％
-I think it's his stomach -I teal indigent
-是吃的东西的问题吗? -他老那样
-Is it something you ate? -He keeps doing that
！@#￥％
I teal indigent
-你饿吗? -不
-Are you hungry? -No
-他疼，是刺痛吗? -不
-He's in pain.Is it a sharp pain? -No!
！@#￥％
Teal indigent!
-味道 -对
-Taste -Yes!
-金属味? -对
-Uh,metallic taste? -Yes!
我马上回来
I'll be right back
我猜也许是钩子断了
I suppose it's also possible that the clasp broke
-但那样你会带着它放包里 -我们打了一架
-But then you'd be carrying the thing around in your purse -We had a fight
我们打了一架，我很生气没顾上 没化装也没带十字架
We had a fight,and I was angry and not thinking straight. And I walked out without my makeup and without my cross
我在杂货铺买的化妆品，可没买十字架 因为他们没有卖护身符的
And I stopped at the drugstore to buy makeup, but I couldn't buy a cross because they don't have an aisle for personal talismans!
你打架了，会淡忘的
So you had a fight.I'm sure it'll blow over
-什么都不为 -当然
-It was about nothing -Of course it was
马克累了，他和担心 他缺乏灵活性
Mark's tired.He's worried.He's got mobility problems
他常为小事烦恼
It's normal to blow up over little things
我不在乎为小事还是大事而吵
I don't mind fighting over little things.And I don't mind fighting over big things
那我可以理解，可我们没来由争吵
That I could understand.But we fight over nothing
你知道，邮箱写“截止下午5点”
You know,a mailbox with a sign that says "last pickup 5:00 P.M."
你知道那是截止送到邮局的时间 还是截止从邮局寄出的时间
Does that mean last pickup to go to the post office or last pickup to leave the post office and be sent out of town?
-你们为邮递时间吵架? -我尝试放弃话题，可他做不到
-You fought over mail delivery? -I tried to get him to drop the subject,but he wouldn't
我跟他说他是对的 他觉得我是在屈就他
I told him he was right, he thought i was being condescending
你是的
You were
-他把我从他生命中驱赶走 -也许你曲解了
-He's pushing me out of his life -Or maybe you're misinterpreting
我曲解你了么？至少我现在注意到了
Did I misinterpret with you?At least this time i recognize it
那样你就可以接受一个说法 两个你爱的男人，离开你更好
That's the benefit of convincing the only two men you've ever loved, they're better off without you
对，都是你的错
Yeah.It's all your fault
你知道“史黛西”在原始希腊语的意思 就是亲密关系杀手
You know,"stacy" in the original greek means relationship killer
我要去洗个脸让自己看起来更象成年人
I'm gonna go wash my face so I look like a grown-up again
喂，是你的电话
Hello.It's for you
-豪斯 -你知道你的电话死了么?
-House -Do you know your phone's dead?
-你就不能充电么? -可以充电？我一直都在买新手机？
-Do you ever recharge your batteries? -they recharge?I just keep buying new phones
我想你该知道你那失语的病人 嘴里有金属味道
I thought you should know your aphasia guy is tasting metal
-他的肌胺酸钎在哪里? -6.8，他肾衰了
-Where's his creatinine? -6.8.He's got kidney failure
卡麦伦给他做透析了 目前稳定
Cameron's got him on dialysis, and he's stable for the moment
不象卡迪，要自杀的模样
Unlike cuddy,who's suicidal
不是脑炎就是脑膜炎 也可能是自体免疫
It's either meningitis or encephalitis.Or maybe autoimmune
太好了，好像一个午餐你就找到方向了
That's perfect. Seems like you really narrowed it down over dinner
-计划是这样的，我们跟豪斯谈…… -试了，他不接
-Here's the plan.We talk to house-- -been trying.He's not answering his cell
无疑要做腰椎穿刺，没选择了
It's obvious we have to do the lumbar puncture.There's no choice anymore
-你得做的准确无误 -你说什么?
-you have to do it just right -What are you talking about?
不管是否做椎刺
Either you've decided to do a lumbar puncture
或是向我开火我就不能向你们开火 一旦我回来掌握大局
or you have to fire me so that I can't fire all of you as soon as I get back in charge
-卡迪在那咆哮呢吗? -如果我知道你会失去联系……
-Is cuddy there ranting? -If I'd known you'd be out of contact--
-他们能应付 -是啊，目前只有三个器官系统失灵
-they can handle it -Right,so far only three organ systems have failed
好吧，他们不行，没关系，那家伙没 稳定到能移动，回自己的办公室咆哮吧
okay,they can't.Doesn't matter.The guy's not stable enough to move.So go rant in your own office
好，完事给我电话
Fine.Call me when you're done
你说做LP是什么意思？我们不会搞砸的
What do you mean by doing the lp just right?We're not gonna screw it up
麻烦的是那家伙知道我们不知道的事
The odds are this guy knows something we dont.
就算他知道生命的真谛 也无法交流
He could know the answer to the meaning of life.The man can't communicate
－有没有他想透露重要情况的迹象 －没有
-have you had any indication that he's tried to communicate something important?   -No
那是因为你们没把他吓到 我肯定你们是“我们会照顾你的”那样
That's because you guys haven't scared him enough. I'm sure you've been all, "we'll take real good care of you."
那他干嘛要说？等你们做试验的时候 跟他说他快死了
Why should he say anything?When you prep him, tell him he's gonna die
砸烂所有希望，别让卡麦伦去，卡迪
Crush all hope. Don't let cameron do it.Cuddy.
有问题么？
You got a problem with any of that?
你会做椎刺，但别抱希望
You're scheduled for a lumbar puncture. But you shouldn't count on that having the answers
-如果你先生继续下滑…… -会死的
-If your husband continues to decline... -you'll die
是否有什么要告诉我们的...
If there's anything you haven't told us...
你的姿势怎样?
how you holding up?
我知道你刚听说的东西很可怕，但...
I know what you just heard is scary as hell,but...
@#￥！^％
couldn't tackle the bear
￥#@^％&！
Couldn't tackle the bear. They took my stain
请注意，因天气原因所有航班取消 请等候通知
Your attention please, due to the weather conditions,all flights are grounded until further notice
底层有休息床服务，我们为不便道歉
Cots are being provided on the lower level.We apologize for the inconvenience
你想让我给你跑下去 抢个有风景的小床么?
You want me to run down and reserve you a cot with a view?
-你的背包呢? -我托运了
-Where's your knapsack? -I checked it through
哦，对，我忘了你没法背着走的
Oh,that's right, I forget it's hard for you to carry and walk
看到坏天气我在机场酒店定了房 最后一间了
I booked a room at the airport hotel when iaw how bad the weather was.It's the last one available
你的腿对付不了在小床上过夜
Your leg can't handle a night on a cot
谢谢
Thanks.
-我好了 -好
-I'm ready -Right
酒店在楼上
Hotel's upstairs
马克知道这个吗?
Does mark know about this?
马克知道当坏事发生时我总有逃生计划
Mark knows when things are bad, I always like to have an escape route planned
我非得知道发生啥事了？
I have to know what's going on here.
你跟马克吵架了，你又躲避我 我就想……
When you have a fight with mark and you try to avoid me, I have to think that--
我感觉受攻击，不想离你近 因为那会导致什么事发生
that I'm feeling vulnerable and I don't wanna be around you because it might lead to something
-对，可然后是酒店房间... -也会导致事情发生
-Right.But then a hotel room... -might also lead to something
那么是哪个呢?
So which is it?
我们的关系就象成瘾一样，会……
Our relationship's like an addiction.It's like-
真好的毒品?
really good drugs?
不，象咖喱肉粉
No,it's like vindaloo curry
-好，是 -很辣的咖喱粉跟红辣椒混合
-Okay,sure -Really,really hot indian curry they make with red chili peppers
我知道，所以我觉得不是成瘾
I know what it is.I didn't think it was addictive
你又烦人又来势凶猛，象……
You're abrasive and annoying and come on way too strong,like--
咖喱肉粉，如果你喜欢咖喱 那也不错啊
vindaloo curry.When you're crazy about curry, that's fine
但无论你多喜欢咖喱 如果吃多了
But no matter how much you love curry, you have too much of it
都会把你的嘴掀开 让你好久好久都不想看见它
it takes the roof of your mouth of and then you never wanna see curry for a really, really long time
但当有一天你醒来，发现……
But you wake up one day and you think...
上帝，我真怀念咖喱
god,I really miss curry
-你是个混账 -我是
-You're a jerk -I Know
-如果你不是正好跟马克吵架的话... -一生一次，你能闭嘴么?
-If you hadn't just had a fight with mark... -for once in your life, will you shut up?
豪斯，我开了扬声器
House.You're on speaker phone
LP怎么样？给我一个浓缩版
How did the lp go?Give me the reader's digest condensed version
初步诊断是感染……
preliminary results are some kind of infection.Which---
-确定下来 -消除无穷大
-narrows it down-- -from infinity.Yeah
按照他器官的衰退程度 也许只有一、两天了
At the rate his organs are deteriorating he's got maybe a day or two
好，等你有结果给我电话吧
Ok,well,call me back when you have something
他想说什么了
he was trying to tell us something
他说什么?
What did he say?
你错了，不是害怕 他跟我说是因为……
You were wrong.It wasn't the fear.He opened up to me when I--
抚慰伤痕的关怀
sympathetic presence after a traumatic moment
古典审讯手段，说什么了?
Classic interrogation technique.What did he say?
-你知道我…… -你一向如此，他说什么了？
-You knew that I'd-- -act the way you always do?Yeah,I did.What did he say?
他无法固定熊
He couldn't tackle the bear
现在我们需要的是失语症英文词典
Now all we need is the english-aphasiac dictionary
失语症患者会试图 找最靠近的意思来表达
A fluent aphasiac retrieves words that are stored somewhere close to the one he wants
他们会失去声音或意思 比如想说table
They can be filed by sound or by meaning.So if he wants to say table
会说成label，或椅子，没法猜
he could say label or he could say chair,or he could just say jabberwocky.There's no way to tell
他还说, "they took my stain."
He also said, "they took my stain."
等一下
Hold on
我下楼去接电话，就不打扰你了 好吗?
I'm gonna take this phone downstairs so I don't disturb you.Is that okay?
好
Sure
让他说，写下来
Keep him talking.Write down everything he says
史黛西，你新买的化妆品 借我好吗？
Stacy...that new makeup you bought,you mind if I borrow it?
-stain什么意思?污点吗？ -不
-What did you mean by stain?Dirt soiled? -No. No
声音怎么样，pain.Brain?
what about rhymes?Uh,pain.Brain?
他快因感染而死了 你们还玩文字游戏?
He's dying from some kind of infection,and you all are playing word games?
还有什么没说的吗?
Is there anything else you haven't told us?
我们再试一次
l-let's start this again
Bear. 是光身子的bare吗?
Bear.Is it bare as in naked?
-深棕显示欲望强烈 -所以我才选啊
-Crimson desire shows up well on sheet rock -That's why i chose it
-你们该找到一个有用的短语了吧 -一些
-you must have gotten one new phrase out of him -Something
我们跟他聊好几个小时了 可能他已经放弃了
We've been talking to him for hours.Maybe he's just given up
你确定已经告诉我所有 在他办公室或家里发现的东西了么？
You sure you told me everything you found at his home and office?
-不，我们有所隐瞒 -也许不是韵或同义词
-No,we're hiding something -Maybe it's not a rhyme or a synonym
还有什么？你认为我们该开始瞎猜吗？
What else is there?You think we should just start guessing randomly?
也许豪斯错了
Maybe house is wrong.
希望那不是思维的终结
Hope that's not the end of the thought
小蔡给他做核磁的时候 他就提到过“stain”
he mentioned stain once before when chase was giving him the mri
-在我们吓唬他之前 -是吗?
-Before we scared him -He did?
在你笔记里
It's in your notes
那么他只在核磁和椎刺时说过话？
so he only talks during mris and lumbar punctures?
-你的理论是他只在针对着他时才说话… -只要他太太不在才说话
-Your theory is he can only talk with a needle in his back or-- -or when his wife's not in the room
越投入，谎言越多
The more devoted, the more reason to lie
-真愤世 -你不同意?
-That's cynical -You disagree?
不，我在得意，我们的小姑娘长大了
No,I'm just kvelling.Our little girl is growing up
好，怎样才能让一个女人 离开她濒死的丈夫呢?
Okay,what's the best way to rip a woman from the side of her dying husband?
他把我叫醒只为让我跟病人的妻子说谎?
He woke me up to lie to a patient's wife?
告诉她有关他们的保险赔付有误传 没什么大不了
Tell her there's been a miscommunication over their insurance coverage.Not a big deal.
告诉我，如果你也打算给我一样 疯狂的主意，那你比豪斯好在哪？
Tell me,if it is your aim to sell me the same crazy ideas that house does, how are you an improvement on house?
我给你带来了咖啡
I brought you a coffee.
-你的飞机叫了20分钟了 -我乘晚一班的
-Your flight's been boarding for 20 minutes -I'll take a later one
格里，他们没你不会走 你把背包托运了
Greg,they can't leave without you.You checked your knapsack
-行了么? -对
-Are we in? -Yeah
你好，我是格里豪斯，你的主治医 你太太不在，说话吧
hi,I'm gregory house.I'm your attending physician Your wife's not there.Start talking.
好了，闭嘴，干的不错，卡麦伦 给他清单
okay,shut up now.Nice work,camer.Give him the list again
-有相象的跟我说， Dirty（脏）? Soiled（污染）? Pain（疼）? Brain（大脑） -对
-Let us know when something sounds right.Dirty? Soiled? Pain? Brain? -Yes!
那能对我们有什么帮助？ 我们已经够注意他大脑的了
where does that get us? We're already paying plenty of attention to his brain
-我们做了核磁，我们做了ct -你肯定他没对pain（疼）有反应吗？
-We've got an mri. We've got a ct -Are we sure he wasn't reacting to pain?
-他用了止痛药 -拜托，小蔡
-He's been on painkillers -come on,chase
毒品不会让他这样 就算是瘾君子也不会
Drugs didn't do this to him.Even if he is an addict
-～！@#￥％ -哦，拜托，安眠药先生，安非他明
-I dissuade the tonal category -Oh please,mr. Sleeping pills.Amphetamines
忽高忽低
Bring me up. Bring me down
乘客格里豪斯请到7号门
will passenger gregory house please report to gate seven?
格里豪斯7号门
Gregory house to gate seven
听过这个吗？建了个房子 每面墙都朝南
Ever hear this one? You build a house.Each wall has a southern exposure
大熊经过，它什么颜色?
Big bear comes wandering by.What color's the bear?
白色，是北极熊，你把房子建在北极了
White.It's a polar bear.You built your house in the north pole
双向，无论你的名字是谁，病人 你是双向情绪吗？
polar.Whatever your name is, patient,are you bipolar?
-什么？我看不见他是不是在点头 -是的
-What? I can't see.Is he nodding? -Yes
Topamax 不是为了非处方减肥 是非处方开给情绪失调者
Topamax isn't just off-label for weight loss.It's off-label for mood disorders
躁郁双向的人白天都很狂躁，夜间抑郁 他用酒精吃药很多年了
Plenty of bipolars are manic in the daytime, depressive at night. He's been medicating for years with alcohol
把坏时间睡过去 那解释了危险的新闻业
Sleeping through the bad hours it explains the danger journalism
都可以解释了，包括厨房的水槽
It explains everything, including the kitchen sink
严格说是厨柜，他开始了计划 可又停下了
Okay,technically it's kitchen cabinets.He starts a project, then he stops
可躁郁双向情绪失调者不会抽搐
Except bipolar disorder does not cause seizures
-也不会肾衰，可他发生了 -对不起，我可以看你的身份证吗?
-and it doesn't shut down your kidneys.But what it does do -excuse me,sir.May I see your id?
-我在打电话 -马上
-I'm on the phone -now,please
-豪斯，怎么了？ -我是医生，这是紧急电话
-House? What is it? -I'm a doctor. This is an emergcy call
-你得跟我走 -我哪也不去
-You have to come with me,sir -I'm not going anywhere
-你觉得你能搞过我吗? -我踢，我咬
-Do you think you're gonna take me on? -I kick, and I bite
你要么登机，要么蹲班房
You're either on that plane, or you're going into custody
豪斯，还在吗？
house? You still there?
双向让人冒险，找刺激，编故事
Being bipolar makes you take risks.You seek excitement.You make up stories
-！@#￥￥％％ -行，也许你的故事合法
-I dime valutate a lever! -Fine,maybe your stories are legit
可人们开始奇怪，对政客造成困扰
But people would start to wonder.Annoyed politicians
整个政府都可能追着你 你无法告诉别人自己是双向情绪者
Entire governments would be on your ass.So you couldn't tell anybody you were bipolar
本来没事，知道你坠入爱河
Which was fine until you fell in love.
你要那个生活，你听说外科手术能治愈
And you wanted that life.And you hear that there's a surgical cure
你可以给爱的女人他要的生活
You can give the woman you love the life she wants.
你所要做的是改变
All you have to do is change
双面扣带束切开术，有人声称对 双向情绪者有效的试验性手术
Bilateral cingulotomy.An experimental surgery that some people claim helps mood disorders
如果是咖马到做的，都无法追踪
And if it's done by gamma knife, there's no trace of cutting
-那就是我们在核磁上看到的疤痕 -那什么也解释不了，因为位置不对
-That's the neural scarring we saw on the mri -Which explained nothing because it wasn't even in the right area
那不是手术，那是秘密
It's not the surgery.It's the secrecy
什么导致高烧?
What causes recurring fever?
神经系统问题 跟咖啡因和安非他明作战
Neurological problems, lethargy that you fight with caffeine pills and amphetamines?
不是你的秘密心理障碍 也不是你的秘密日用药品
It wasn't your secret psych disorder.It wasn't your secret daily drug use
而是你去加拉加斯或布宜诺斯爱力斯 做手术的秘密旅行
It was the secret trip for your secret surgery in caracas or buenos aires
那不管用，就算你给厨房修厨柜
Which,by the way, didn't work, given the state of your kitchen cabinets
-豪斯 -闭嘴
-house! -Shut up
怎么了?
What's going on?
他没事吗?
Is he right?
你的医生比我了解你
Your doctors know you better than I do
电话上的人都没见过你 也比我了解你
That man on the speaker phone, he never even met you,and he knows you better than I do
-你爱我? -是
-You love me? -Yes. Yes
你只是不信任我
You just don't trust me
做血液检查片，别用电脑了这次
get some blood on a slide.Do not put it through a computer this time
好
Yep
脑疟疾
cerebral malaria
我给他静脉注射奎纳定
I'll get him started on intravenous quinidine
如果人类给他做过肉眼检查
If a human being had actually looked at his blood anywhere along the way
而不只是用电脑
instead of just running tests through the computer
早就发现寄生虫了
the parasites would have jumped right out at them
电子时代的代价
The price of the electronic age
福莱，她会回来的
fletch.She'll be back
给她时间让她想念你
Give her time to miss you
-我指着你给我弄出不让飞名单呢 -你的病人没事吧?
-I'm counting on you to get me off the no-fly list -Is your patient gonna be all right?
-躯体的？机会挺多 -躯体?
-Physically, his chances are good -Physically?
两个不该在一起的人
Two people who weren't meant to be together
也没准有完美结局呢 因为他们俩都抱很大希望
Maybe they'll get a happy ending just because they both want it so much
-对，通常如此 -他的爱使他有信心改变自己
-Yeah,that's usually the way it works -He loved her enough to convince himself he could change
可他不行，对吗?
But he couldn't, could he?
谢谢
Thank you
你知道伍迪艾伦怎么形容关系?
You know what woody allen said about relationships?
-无理智的疯狂，可都要经历，因为…… -我们需要咖喱
-Irrational and crazy,but we go through it all because-- -we need the curry